有个病人在等你看病 瞧?
You have a patient waiting. See?
我在等一个复诊患者
I'm waiting for a follow-up.
如果你说的是Casdin先生abc恐怕他和你今天其他预约
If you're talking about mr. Casdin,heabchas a "deceased" sticker on his file,
复诊的病人一样早已不在人世了
as do all the other follow-ups youabchave scheduled for today.
哇
Whoops.
我整个冬天都在感冒
I had colds all winter.
我恐怕在这屋子待太久了abc可现在是春天 不是么?
Well,I've been in this roomabca while,but it's spring now,right?
我有些征兆 似乎我得了重病
I feel run-down like maybeabcsomething bigis coming on.
征兆 拜托 说详细点 喉咙痛吗?
Run-down. Come on,giveabcme something. Sore throat?
不痛
No.
- 流鼻涕吗?abc- 没有
- Runny nose?abc- No.
我知道这很怪 我是个护士abc能不能给我做全血细胞计数或甲亢的检查
I know it sounds weird,I'm a nurse,butabccould you run maybe a cbc or thyroid up--
Cuddy医生 快来会诊啊
Dr. Cuddy,I need a consult.
在她发作停止前abc我还是回办公室琢磨琢磨这是啥病好了
Until she stops seizing,I may as well goabcback to my office and get my diagnosis on.
她尿失禁
She's urinating on herself.
她癫痫发作 如果没有尿失禁--
She's having a seizure.Ifabcshe hadn't peed--
尿是绿色的
It's green.
真稀奇
Interesting.
35岁女性 老人疗养院护士长
35-year-old woman. Head ofabcnursing at an old-age home.
神经系统症状和"P"?
Neurological symptoms and "p"?
哦 绿尿 我懂了 形容得太好了
Oh,green pee. I get it. Nice.
绿色的"神经系统"
"Neuro" is also written in green.
难道她的神经系统症状也是绿色的?
Does that mean she has greenabcneurological symptoms as well?
现在起我用两种颜色
From now on,I'm gonna use two colors.
绿色表示嘲讽
Green indicates irony.
假单胞菌感染
Pseudomonas infection.
没有发热 中毒吗?
She'd have a fever. Toxins?
为什么接这个病例?
Why are we taking this case?
陛下 欢迎您
Welcome,your lordship.
正准备向您呈上早晨简报
We were just preparingabcyour morning briefing.
抱歉 迟到了
Sorry I'm late.
没错 绿尿的确符合你接手病例的abc唯一准则
And,yes,green pee does meet the onlyabcdiagnostic requirement you care about--
很有趣 但有必要接它吗?
it's interesting. But is itabcworth us taking this case?
我来挑选病例 "我们"没的选abc你只有接受的份
"Us" aren't taking anything.abcI'm taking. You're accepting.
好吧 我接受了
Okay,I accept.
她有成年发作型癫痫abc还挺喜欢圣帕特里克节的绿色啤酒
She has adult-onset epilepsy,and sheabcreally likes those st. Patrick's day beers.
去她家和工作的地方abc搜搜有毒物质和感染源
Go check out the house and theabcoffice for toxins and infections.
神经检查无异常 而且癫痫没有再发
Her neuro exam was normal.abcNo subsequent seizures.
这不危及生命 也不重要
It's not life-threatening.abcIt's not important.
幸亏你也是这样
Luckily neither are you.
- 没事吧?abc- 还好
- You okay?abc- I'm fine.
今天早上你竟敢和House对峙
You and house this morning,theabcway you were arguing.
意见不同并不代表质疑他
Airing disagreementsabcdoesn't qualify as arguing.
伙计 说出来吧abc我只是想帮你 我们是朋友
Come on,man. I'm just tryingabcto help. We're friends.
昨晚跟你一起打电玩的abc400个日本青少年才是你的好朋友吧
There are 400 japanese teenagers you were playingabchalo  with last night you're better friends with.
你的战士才应该关心关心他们的战士
Your avatar should ask theirabcavatars how they're doing.
就算我们工作之外不大玩得来abc我也把你当作是好朋友
I consider you a good friend even ifabcwe don't hang that much outside work.
我不是和他吵架
I wasn't arguing with him.
就是吵架啊
You kinda were.
好吧 就算是吵架 瞧这 我说对了
Fine,I was. And youabcknow what,I was right.
你上当了 亚甲基蓝abc绿尿就是它明显的副作用
You got conned. Methylthioniniumabcchloride. Notable side effect,green urine.
她是个护士 清楚用药剂量abc也知道怎样扮演癫痫发作
She's a nurse. She knows theabcdosage. Knows how to fake a seizure.
尿出豌豆汤abc就能使她整周都得到医生的密切观察
She pees pea soup and gets the warmabcattention of doctors all week long.
她是装病 你被戏弄了
She's a munchausen,and you're her mark.
你的推断只是来源于abc在老人院里发现的抗老年痴呆药
So you're insight is based on discoveringabcan anti-alzheimer's drug at an old-age home.
没理由药会在她桌上找到
No good reason it'dabcbe sitting in her desk.
试过当众尿失禁吗? 这很难的
You ever tried to pee onabcyourself in public? It's not easy.
抱歉 我加入过兄弟会 我们绝不当众撒尿
Sorry,I rushed the jewishabcfrat. We peed in private.
如果是假的癫痫 我能看得出来
For good reason. I canabcspot a fake seizure.
意味着癫痫是真的 那么她的病因是苯酚
Which means this was real. Whichabcmeans her problem is phenol.
苯酚吗
Carbolic acid?
也许是1890年abc当她在治疗痛风时无意中吸入的
Yeah,maybe she accidentally inhaled someabcat a gout treatment facility circa 1890.
苯酚仍用于抗生素喷喉剂
It's still inabcsome antiseptic throat sprays.
她整个冬天都用那玩意来治感冒
She's been chugging it allabcwinter for her colds.
苯酚解释了癫痫和尿液
Phenol explains theabcseizure and the urine.
她得一天喝完5瓶苯酚才会这样
She'd have to drink five bottles a day.
所以我才觉得你们搜屋时abc会轻而易举找到证据
Which is why I'm sure you won't have troubleabcdiscovering evidence of it when you search her house.
拜拜
Bye.
给她用抗苯酚的活性炭吸附治疗吧
And you can start her on charcoalabchemoperfusion for the phenol poisoning.
你当真了啊?
Seriously?
噢 喷喉剂是你编的
Oh,you were lying about the throat spray.
这下理顺了
That does make more sense.
为什么你要戏弄Taub?
So why are you wasting taub's time?
因为我不想他知道abc我要费时间去推翻他癫痫是伪装的理论
Because I don't want him to know that I'm wastingabcmy time disproving his fake seizureheory. Zip.
Chris?
你是Chris Taub 对吧?
Chris taub,right?
Neil Zane
Neil zane.
我是你高中低两届的师弟abc还记得吗?
I was two years under you atabccollegiate high,remember?
当然记得
Sure.
你现在是这里的大医生了哦?
So you're some big doctor here now?
我是这里的医生 你呢?
I'm a doctor. You?
我在大学做经济学的演讲abc摔了一跤 伤了腿
Well,I was speaking at an econ course over atabcthe university. I tripped and banged my leg.
我有时间 跟我来
I have some time. Come with me.
检查结果出来了?
Tests back?
头部CT无异常
Head ct was negative.
甲状腺摄入率和腹部B超结果呢?
What abouta thyroid uptakeabcor abdominal ultrasound?
不谈这
Sure.
我能不能先对着你的脸闪光?
How 'bout I flash some lights inabcfront of your face first?
你想让我癫痫再发作吗?
You want me to have another seizure?
除非查明了病因 否则就得请你出院
We're gonna have to give up theabcroom unless we can confirm a problem.
好吧
Okay.
妈的
Damn it.
天啊
Oh,god.
- 请原谅我 真是对不起abc- 你有什么好担心的?
- Please forgive me. I'm so sorry.abc- What are you worried about?
你顶多因为欺诈在牢里待上一晚abc我可是要去向手下承认 他猜对了
Maybe a night in jail for fraud. I have toabcgo tell one of my employees he was right.
我不是装病abc你如果不帮我 我会死的
I'm not a munchausen. I'mabcgonna die unless you help me.
你最好想些更新颖的点子
You'll have to come up withabcsomething more original.
一只猫告诉我我会死
A cat predicted my death.
猫不是好医生
Cats make terrible doctors.
噢 错了 女人才不是好医生abc你秀逗了
Oh,no,wait,that's women. You're screwed.
你怎么摔的?
How'd you slip?
我这阵子一直有点晕眩
Oh,I've had thisabcdizziness problem for a while now.
有没有查过内耳炎?
You get checked for labyrinthitis?
吃了一周的抗生素 没效
On antibiotics for a week. No difference.
先躺下
Lie down a sec.
噢 等等 我晕
Whoa,whoa,I'm dizzy.
这是正常的
That's normal.
你教什么?
So what are you teaching?
创业学 我是OSTTECH的老总abc我们制造医疗仪器
Entrepreneurship. I'm a ceo,osttechabcindustries. We make medical devices.
好了 坐起来吧
All right,you can sit up.
你检查出了什么? 我--
So did that tellabcyou anything?Did I--
噢 老天--你把我治好了
oh,my god. The--youabcjust cured me.
我猜你内耳可能有点钙沉积abc我只是把它转了一下
I figured you had a tiny calcium depositabcin your inner ear;I just shifted it around.
我都看了3个医生了
I've seen three doctors for this.
- 我请你吃饭吧abc- 不用了
- I'm buying you dinner.abc- Forget it.
来吧 我也投资了俱乐部abc今晚出去玩玩吧
Come on. I'm also in investorinabca club. We'll make it a night out.
不了 我结婚了 而且很无趣
No,I'm married,boring.
我也认识一些已婚人士 他们挺有趣的啊
I know some married peopleabcwho aren't boring.
几年前 我也和他们一样abc祝你好运了
A few years back,I wasabcone of them. Good luck.
如果要先杀后奸 一定要严格遵守以上顺序
If you're gonna kill me and rapeabcme,please do it in that order.
这就是那只猫 Debbie 你听说过吗?
This is the cat,debbie.abcHave you heard of her?
Debbie 抱歉 没有姓氏记不起来
Debbie.Sorry butabcwithout a last name--
它上过新闻 它自小就被我们抚养
She was in the news. Weabcfound her as a kitten.
它住在老人院
She lives in the nursing home.
它只会在将死之人旁边睡觉
She only sleeps next toabcpeople when they're about to die.
去年有10个病人死去
Ten patients in the last year.
昨天我坐在椅子上 它也那样躺在我身边
And then yesterday she did it toabcme while I was sitting on my couch.
拜托 所有职员abc甚至医生们都知道它很准的
Please,the whole staff,the doctorsabceven,we all know this is real.
你能晚点再来吗?
Can you come back later?
我要和尼日利亚公主商量些事儿
I have some business I'm conductingabcwith the prince of nigeria.
看看这录像 可以证明我没骗你
Just watch this video.abcIt'll prove I'm not lying.
House医生 拜托了
Dr. House,I'm begging you.
胸口
Chest.
快点啊! 8秒钟得不到关注 她就要不行了
Quick! Before she goesabcwithout attention for eight seconds.
House
House.
她是装的 那只猫说的
She's faking. The cat told me.
你听
Listen.
呼吸音微弱 说明支气管痉挛了
Soft breath sounds.abcMeans it's bronchospasm.
这装不了
Can't fake that.
猫咪Debbie总是在大厅里逡巡abc她是秘密世界里的女皇
Debbie the cat spends most of her time just prowlingabcthe halls,the queen of her own private world.
老实说 我不喜欢他们对美国偶像的删改
Gotta say,I don't think the changes they'veabcmade to american idol really work for me.
当Debbie爬上病人的床并躺下abc我们就会打电话让家属过来
When debbie climbs on a patient's bed and goes toabcsleep,we call the loved ones and tell them to come in.
你要接这个病例? 她是个疯子
You want to treat her? She's a nut job.
我们不都有些小古怪吗?
Don't we all have quirks?
就是这些特异之处abc让我们显得更有人味儿
Aren't those eccentricities whatabcmake us human?
Debbie就像是把人们送到另一世界的使者
It's like debbie's here on earthabcto bring people to the other side.
- 接受采访的医生也同意那只猫能--abc- 疯子也会生病
- Also agreed is the cat doesabcseem-- - Nutjobs get sick too.
那么说 你认为这猫的事是个忽悠
So you think this cat story is nonsense.
也承认她先前的症状是装出来的
And you admit sheabcfaked her earlier symptoms.
但你还是认为她有病?
But you still think she'sabcactually sick now?
任何事用这种语调说出来abc都会显得很荒唐
Well,anything would sound ridiculousabcif you said it in that voice.
确定她是在装病abc要么我马上让她出院
Confirm she's faking or I'mabcgonna have to kick her out.
这种语调又来了
There's that voice again.
我给你24小时
I'll give you 24 hours.
连续的?
Consecutive?
你在干什么?
What are you doing?
不 邦德先生 我想你死
No,mr. Bond,I expect you to die.
支气管痉挛 开始
Bronchospasm,go.
- 支气管炎abc- 没有咳嗽 没有发烧
- Bronchitis.abc- No cough,no fever.
而且Blofeld不抽雪茄abc(007电影反派角色)
And blofeld didn't smoke a cigar.
没准他抽 这位仁兄有个基地abc说明他很有钱
He might have. Dude hadabca lair. Means he was rich.
有钱人喜欢抽好雪茄abc有时还会用来送人
Rich people enjoy a good stogie.abcSometimes send them as gifts.
Taub 我这番牵强的比喻abc是不是听起来另有所指?
Hey,taub,did that sound like I was awkwardlyabctrying to segue into making a point?
是的
Yes.
- 肺气肿abc- CT显示肺没有问题
- Emphysema.abc- Lungs were clean on the ct.
经过训练的狗可以预测糖尿病昏迷abc癫痫发作 它们能嗅出癌症的味道
Dogs can be trained to predict diabeticabccomas,epileptic seizures;they can smell cancer.
可能这只猫也有这本领
It is possibleabcthere's something in this cat.
更有可能的是 这一切只是巧合
It's more possible thatabcit was just a coincidence.
世上有1000万所疗养院 1亿只宠物猫
10 million nursing homes.abc100 million pet cats.
总有这么一两只中头奖
One of them was bound toabcpick a few winners.
Debbie在你发现病人症状前abc便预测了她不对劲
Debbie was able to predict there was somethingabcwrong with the patient before you were.
难道这也是巧合?
Is that a coincidence too?
也许这只猫并不能预测死亡
Maybe the cat didn't predict a thing.
而是带来了死亡
Might have caused the deaths.
我们应该听听Ted Nugent的歌abc(有首歌名为"猫爪热")
We shoulda listened to ted nugent.
可能是猫爪热或者内脏幼虫移行症
Yeah,it could be cat scratchabcfever or visceral larva migrans.
也许疗养院其他人的死与它无关abc但她正在杀死Morgan
Maybe he didn't kill everyone at theabcnursing home,but it may be killing morgan.
寄生虫从猫身上蹦到了这位猫女郎的肺里
The worms hop from theabccat to the cat lady's lungs.
这我能接受
I could buy that.
这些雪茄是给我的
Those cigars were for me.
嘿 差点忘问了 为什么有个总裁abc会送你一大盒古巴雪茄?
Hey,that reminds me,why is some fancyabcceo sending you a box of cuban cigars?
这和你的财政危机有关吗?
Is it related to your money worries?
什么财政危机?
What money worries?
根据他今早没吃松饼这一事实
Extrapolating from the fact thatabche's been skipping his morning muffin,
我敢断定 他去年在市场上赔掉了所有积蓄
I'd say that he lost almost allabchis money on the market last year.
我在减肥
I'm on a diet.
根据他忘记退出的网上投资账户abc也能得出这结论 但主要还是根据松饼
I'm also extrapolating from the online portfolioabcyou forgot to log off,but it's mostly the muffins.
检查下她的肺有没寄生虫
Scope her for worms in the lungs.
我们可以进去帮忙
We could help out in there.
没错 得4个人才能从这疯女人abc的肺里头找出根本不存在的虫子
Yeah,it takes at least four people to lookabcinside a crazy woman's lungs for imaginary worms.
看来你心情不太好呢
So you're in a good mood again.
要我再次表明心迹abc你才相信我是个可靠的朋友?
You need another speechabcabout what a great friend I am?
我告诉我妻子不必节衣缩食abc但看来有必要了
I'm telling my wife we don'tabcneed to downsize,but maybe we do.
你真的赔光了所有钱?
You really lost all that money?
我不在乎钱abc只是觉得对不起Rachel
I don't care about the money.abcI just feel bad for rachel.
你如今的际遇 和她嫁给你时迥然不同abc任何人都很难接受
She married a guy in one situation andabcended up with another;that's hard on anyone.
谢了 听到有人说我妻子嫁我只为钱abc我感觉好多了
Thanks. Makes me feel muchabcbetter hearing my wife's a gold digger.
不 我意思是她当时嫁给了一个abc高高在上 事业有成的外科医生
No,I just meant she married this masterabcof the universe,successful surgeon,
现在却给一个疯子科学家打下手...
and now he's basically,you know,aabcflunky for this mad scientist...
但他能拯救生命 所以是好事
who saves lives,so that's good.
肺里没有寄生虫
There are no worms in the lungs.
还有什么会引起支气管痉挛?
What else could cause bronchospasm?
- 严重的酸反流abc- 没有食道炎症状 不是反酸
- Severe acid reflux.abc- No esophagitis. It's not reflux.
你推急救车干嘛?
Why are you pushing a crash cart?
因为有时病人需要急救
Because patients sometimes crash.
而且他们还没发明急救拖拉机abc好让我在走道里疯狂飙车
And they haven't yet invented a crash tractorabcfor me to drive wildly around the hallways.
我们来昏迷病人的病房干什么?
Why are we in the coma patients' room?
你真的认为这只猫可以预测死亡?
You actually think the cat isabcgoing to predict someone's death?
不 我知道它不能预测死亡
No,I know the cat the not goingabcto predict anyone's death.
所以我要用科学的方法进行验证--
Then I willabchave scientifically disproved--
你并非为了病人才留下这只猫abc而是为了这只猫才留下了病人
You didn't keep this patient despite theabccat. You kept this patient because of the cat.
你害怕两者真的有关
You're scared there's something to it.
如果能证实引领我们走向彼岸世界abc的万能上帝并不存在 我会这么做
If I could prove the non-existence of an omniscientabcgod who lovingly guides us to the other side,I would.
同样我也要证明死神猫不存在
Cat version's gonna have to do.
你害怕了?
Are you scared?
猫的脑子总是处于阿尔法状态
Cats brains are always in alpha mode.
有几例实验表明心灵感应发生于这一状态
The few scientific tests that have seemed toabcconfirm physic phenomena,that's where it takes place.
拜托告诉我 你是在开玩笑abc好让我不用开除你
Please tell me that you wereabckidding so I won't have to fire you.
我在开玩笑
I was kidding.
我们的病人仍是人类 对不?
We still have a human patient,right?
会不会是空气中有过敏原?
Airborne allergens possible?
皮肤试验呈阴性
Skin test was negative.
也许肺部更敏感
Lungs may be more sensitive.
或者House搞砸了
Or house just screwed up.
如果你把嘈杂的呼吸音听成了微弱的
If you misinterpreted the breathabcsounds as soft instead of loud,
这就是喉痉挛而不是支气管痉挛了
it's laryngospasmabcinstead of bronchospasm,
受到惊吓就可能导致发病abc正是她的问题所在
which you can get from a simpleabcpanic attack,which she was having.
我也听了她的肺音 你是说我也搞砸了?
I also heard the lung soundsabctoo,taub. You saying I screwed up?
"搞砸"也许有点尖锐 但是的
"Screwed up"is maybe too harsh,but yes.
你不用看一下他们的病历?
Don't you want to check their charts?
当然不用 这是个双盲实验
Of course not. This is a double-blind.
我不想通过潜意识向Teddy透露abc哪个人病得比较厉害
I don't want to even subconsciouslyabcsignal to teddy which one's the sickest.
她叫Debbie
Her name's debbie.
这人手臂上的是不是风团?
Are those welts on that guy's arm?
我们进来时有吗?
Were they here when we got here?
他对猫严重过敏
He has a severe cat allergy.
- 这事从未发生abc- 你看Debbie
- That never happened.abc- Look at debbie.
好消息 这位...Limpert先生
Good news,mister...limpert,
只要你今晚死不了abc你就最终为世界做了件好事
when you don't die tonight you will finallyabchave done something good for the world
为你作为...消防员的一生赎罪了
as opposed to your life as A... fireman.
Foreman的空气过敏原论最靠谱
Foreman's airborne allergen theoryabcmakes the most sense.
给那位猫女郎做个乙酰甲胆碱激发试验
Do a methacholine challenge onabccatgirl to check it out.
叫你别管那只"死神猫"了
I told you to get rid of "death cat".
- 你看到这儿有猫么?abc- 我看到了猫砂盒
- Do you see a cat?abc- I see a litter box.
这儿有位残疾人士 Cuddy医生
This is a disability,dr. Cuddy.
- 他并非每回都能及时赶到洗手间abc- 他也抓老鼠不成?
- Can't make it to the men's room on time.abc- On the mice too?
有老鼠恰恰证明我没有猫
Well,now you see the mice actuallyabcprove that I don't have a cat.
这是...肿瘤科的转基因实验老鼠吗?
Are these-- are these theabcgenetically modified lab mice from oncology?
转基因的味道更好
Genetically modified for tastiness.
让那只猫还有你的病人出院
Get rid of the cat,andabcget rid of your patient.
我的小组正在做乙酰甲胆碱激发试验
My team's doing a methacholine challenge.
你的小组已经做完试验了abc结果呈阴性反应
Your team just completed a methacholineabcchallenge,which came up negative.
谁把试验的事告诉你了? Taub?
Who told you about the test? Taub?
我可没说 不过是的
I'll never say,but yes.
她的气管收紧了 我亲耳听到的
Her airways clamped down. I heard it.
我们把她撵到大街上abc这种情况可能再发生
We kick her onto theabcstreet,it could happen again.
真希望有只黑猫警长来警告你
I wish there was a lawsuitabccat. It could warn you.
很抱歉 如果你不打发她出院abc我就要让保安动手了
I'm sorry,but if you won't escort herabcout,I'll have to get security to do it.
我们抽根烟权当告别吧
You're joining me for a good-bye smoke.
我不吸烟
I don't smoke.
好事 如果你不想周围的abc七年级生觉得你很酷的话
Fine. If you don't want the seventhabcgraders to think you're cool.
我翻了下你的皮包abc有星座运程 幸运符
I went through your purse.abcHoroscopes. Good luck charms.
你上过很好的大学abc很好的护士学校
You went to a goodabccollege,good nursing school.
也就是说 你并非一直是个迷信的蠢蛋
So you weren't always aabcsuperstitious idiot.
- 我不是迷信--abc- 那四年前是怎么回事?
- I'm not a super-- - How 'boutabcfour years,that sound right?
从那时起 你不再信赖家庭保险计划abc而转投现在的信仰
That's when you switched from a familyabcinsurance plan to the one you're on now.
我结婚了 后来又离了
I was married. I got divorced.
在这之前两年 你注射过水痘疫苗
Two years before that,youabcgot chicken pox shots,
成人只有在有小孩子时abc才会注射这种疫苗
which you only get inabcadulthood when you have a kid.
或者说 你曾经有过小孩abc但从来没有孩子来探望你
Or I should say when you had a kidabcbecause no kid has come to visit you.
我由此联想到abc曾经发生过不幸的事
Which all makes meabcthink something bad happened.
是我的继子 Timothy
It was my step son,timothy.
怎么回事?
What happened?
他当时在学校里
He was in school.
正在吃早餐 不小心呛到了
He was having his morningabcsnack. And he choked.
老师用尽一切办法 也没能把他救回来
And the teacher saw it,and they didabceverything that they were supposed to.
他不应该这么死去
He shouldn't have died.
你想为这一切寻求解释
You want to make it make sense.
难道不该寻找么?
What's wrong with that?
这是徒劳无功的 就错在这儿
It's meaningless,is what's wrong.
既不能救回你孩子的性命
What's wrong is that it doesn'tabcdo a thing to bring your kid back
也不能让你和前夫破镜重圆
or put you and your ex together again.
你脖子上出现了皮疹
Rash on your neck.
也许对Cuddy来说还不够
Probably not enough for cuddy.
- 我无法呼吸abc- 嘿 医生
- I can't breathe.abc- Hey,doc.
这呼吸音你听着微弱吗 医生?
Breath sound soft to you,doc?
万岁! 你正式进入了病人行列
Hooray! You're officially sick.
Churg-Strauss综合症最为符合abc(变应性肉芽肿血管炎)
Churg-strauss fits best.
解决方案如下-- Taub把盒子清理干净
Here's the plan-- taub,youabcchange the litter box.
太可悲了
This is pathetic.
我在绿色小便女病例上向你叫板abc所以你要惩罚我?
You're still punishing me for callingabcyou out on the green urine lady?
不 是惩罚你向Cuddy揭发我
Nope,this is for ratting me out to cuddy.
我又没逼你道歉 只是让你abc把盒子里的便便铲出去罢了
I'm not asking you to apologize,justabcscoop some poop out of a box.
去清理吧
Just clean it.
- 让House自己干abc- 是啊 他会干的
- Let house do it.abc- Yeah,that'll happen.
他不会让这房子弥漫着一股猫嘘嘘的味道
He won't just continue toabclet our room smell like cat pee.
- 下次换我清理好了abc- 我不玩了
I'll clean it next time. I'm outta here.
既然你的宝贵一课上完了abc我去给病人做检查
Now that you've delivered that importantabclesson,I'm gonna go test the patient.
怎么 难道怕你的背包会死掉?
What,you think your bag's gonna die now?
现在换惩罚我了? 因为你觉得我迷信abc这跟你有什么关系?
Now you're punishing me because youabcthink I'm superstitious? What do you care?
这跟我没啥关系
It's not so much about me caring per se.
我只是好奇你咋会这么笨abc别人说什么都信
It's more about me wondering whyabcyou're such a credulous idiot.
13 给病人注射类固醇abc治疗Churg-Strauss综合症
Thirteen,start the patient onabcsteroids for the churg-strauss.
除非我们也有话题要争论
Unless we have something weabcneed to argue about.
这可是好东西啊
This is good stuff.
最棒的
The best.
这可是用最近下岗的abc对冲基金经理的汗液酿制
It's made from the distilled sweat ofabcrecently laid-off hedge fund managers.
难得出来轻松下 你不开心吗?
Aren't you happy you came out tonight?
我本不打算出来的abc但今天工作上有点阻滞
Yeah. I wasn't actually goingabcto,but not the greatest day at work.
我以前也有间这样的办公室
I used to have an office like this.
以前?
Used to?
当我还是个整容医生时
When I was a plastic surgeon.
直至有一天 我用人生来作赌注 而且--
But one day I tookabcstock of my life and--
全盘皆输
Screw it.
我和一个合伙人的女儿搞上了
I had an affair with the daughterabcof one of my partners.
他们答应不把事情说出去abc我答应退出竞争
They signed a non-disclosure.abcI signed a non-compete.
但讽刺的是 到头来我向老婆坦白了
And the funny thing is Iabcwound up telling my wife anyway.
你喜欢你的工作吗?
You like your job?
和你一样 和所有人一样abc有高潮也有低潮
Same as you. Same as everyone.abcIt has its ups and downs.
你这么说是为了让我好过点
You're lying to make me feel better.
是的 这是最棒的 我控制一切abc像霸占了所有玩具的孩子
Yeah,it's the best. I'm inabccharge,you know? I'm a kid with toys.
说起这个 你觉得这样品怎样?
Speaking of which,what doabcyou think of the prototype?
棒极了
It's amazing.
要能缩短半英寸就更好了
Gotta make it aabchalf-inch smaller though.
- 你说真的?abc- 我的手很小 戴6.5号手套
- You serious?abc- I got small hands,6.5 gloves,
和女医生的差不多abc她们才是最大的潜力市场
like women surgeons,whichabcare your fastest-growing market
女生得用两只手才能摁到开关
Meaning the girls would have toabcuse two hands to hit the switch.
我为什么还要付手下那帮蠢材工钱?
Why do I bother paying theabcidiots that work for me?
把你喝的泔水放下abc我来开一支真正的好东西
Put down that crap you're drinking,becauseabcI am breaking out the really good stuff.
怎么了?
What's wrong?
我刚才去洗手间 我的小便--
I went to the bathroom.abcMy urine--
- 又变绿了?abc- 变成褐色了
- Green again?abc- It's brown.
我什么也没做 真的
I didn't do anything,honest.
* 我是个从不拒绝人的女孩 *
* I'm just a girl who can't say no *
她很可能还在装病
It is possible she's still faking.
支气管痉挛可不是装的
She didn't fake the for the bronchospasm.
你认为她装病 还有的放矢
You think she's faking someabcstuff but not other stuff?
也许她患了变异型"乔森综合症"
Maybe she's "unchausen".
我只是觉得褐色尿液完全不合理
I'm just saying theabcbrown urine doesn't make sense.
- 怎么了?abc- 没事
- What?abc- Nothing.
我们排除了所有导致尿液褐色的病因
We've ruled out every possibleabccause for brown urine.
尿液不带血 肝和肾都好好的
No blood in the urine.abcLiver and kidneys fine.
褐色的可能是排泄物 瘘管--
Brown could beabcfecal.A fistula--
我们也查了
We checked.
我们怎知她的尿液至今仍是褐色?
How do we know the urine is still brown?
一定是 一旦变成褐色--
Had to be. Onceabcyou've gone brown--
既然我们排除了所有可能病因abc会不会只是表面看来是褐色的?
If we've ruled out everything that can make theabcurine brown,what if it just looked brown?
如果绿染料依然在系统里abc绿加什么变褐?
If the green dye never left herabcsystem,what plus green makes brown?
紫色
Purple.
结肠癌导致的牛链球菌感染
Strep bovis infection from colon cancer.
肿瘤伴随症出现支气管痉挛
Paraneoplastic syndrome wouldabcexplain the bronchospasm.
找瘘管的时候做了镜检 没肿瘤
We scoped her when we checked forabcthe fistula. There's no tumor.
噢 不
Oh,no.
我也不怕伞
I wasn't scared by the umbrella either.
什么? 不是所有事都关乎你 Kutner
What? Not everything's about you,kutner.
我知道这很傻 只是--我不是全知的abc我也不想被邀请--
I realize it's stupid. I just--I don'tabcknow everything.I don't want to invite--
很好 我还以为你因为亲人去世abc而变得迷信
Great,'cause I thought your superstitiousnessabchad to do with your folks being killed.
但"你很傻"也讲得通
But "you're stupid" works just as well.
这儿为什么有个梯子?
Why is there a ladder here?
噢 忘了
Oops. Forgot that one.
镜检没胶囊摄像机好abc给她吃个 找到肿瘤
Scopes don't work as well as pillcams.abcGive her one. Find the tumor.
跟我来 小Taub
Come with me,tiny taub.
过来
Come on.
很抱歉我又来晚了
Sorry I was late again.
我的破房子离这儿很远
I've got a longabccommute from the poor house.
雇你时就知道了
Knew it when I hired you.
你终究会怀念赚大把钱的日子abc像你那个大亨新朋友一样神气
You'd eventually miss the money,beingabcthe big shot like your new ceo friend,
夜总会敲在你手上的印章就是个提示
if that night club stamp onabcyour hand is any indication.
- 别担心 我没想走abc- 我知道
- Don't worry,I'm not quitting.abc- I know.
一个情愿签不竞争协议abc也不告诉妻子他有外遇的人
Guy who signs a non-compete insteadabcof just telling his wife that he cheated
- 怕是没勇气走的abc- 错误的例子 我告诉她了
- doesn't have the guts to quit.abc- Bad example. I did tell her.
是内疚 不是胆量
From guilt,not from courage.
勇敢地背着我投靠Cuddy
And bravely runningabctouddy behind my back.
每天还超人般地冲进来上班
Arriving heroically to work every day.
胆小的雇员干不了活
Cowards make lousy employees.
或许你是胆小鬼 或许你会走
Maybe you're a coward,maybeabcyou're quitting.
不管怎样 我都有麻烦了
Either way,I'm screwed.
你会知道猫能多快杀死一个人
You will note howabcfaster pussy cat kill,kill
死神正蜷曲在那个昏迷的人身边
has snuggled up by coma guy over there.
更重要的是 她昨天就这样干了
And more importantly,sheabcdid yesterday as well.
他却还在呼吸 弄清楚了吗?
And he's still breathing. We done?
谢谢你让我看这个
Thank you for showing me this.
但或许只是她不能适应新环境
But maybe she's justabcconfused in this new environment.
1844年 纽约一名传道士abc将圣经中出现的几处日期相加
In 1844,a preacher in upstate newabcyork added up some dates in the bible
预言基督将再次降临
and predicted jesus' return.
追随者抛弃所有 聚到一片空地上
His followers gave away all theirabcpossessions and showed up in a field.
猜猜谁没来
Guess who didn't show.
传道士说 他算错了abc于是第二个月 来了更多的人
So the preacher said that he miscalculated,and theyabcwent right back the next month but with more followers.
每次他被证明错误 都让大家更加相信
Every time he was irrefutably provedabcwrong,it redoubled everyone's belief.
我知道我就像他们一样
I know I sound just like them.
但我也知道你错了
But I also know you're wrong.
不好的事将降临在我身上
Something terrible's gonna happen to me.
你是想向她证明她不会死?
You trying to prove toabcher she's not dying?
这太蠢了 她没准会死
That would be dumb,asabcshe might be dying.
这女人没了孩子
This woman lost her kid.
你为什么要攻击abc能让她有些许安慰的信仰?
Why are you attacking beliefs thatabcgive hera little bit of comfort?
我不在乎迷信是不是让她好过
I don't care if her superstitionsabcmake her feel better.
我只想她能考虑清楚
I just want her to think more clearly.
噢 或许这能让她和你一样高兴
Oh,maybe that couldabcmake her as happy as you are.
我们去哪?
Where are we going?
做实验
Experimenting.
停下 Wilson医生 这一点都不可爱
Stop it,dr. Wilson. It'sabcjust not cute anymore.
你已经在那个昏迷的人身上做了实验
You already experimented on the coma guy.
还没能证明你的观点?
Haven't you proved your point?
病人不相信
Not to the patient.
成千上万对魔法猫流口水的笨蛋也不肯信
And not to the millions of idiots who drooledabcover that news item about the magic cat.
你为什么总纠结这个?
Why are you so obsessed with this?
干嘛不直接叫她白痴然后放过大家?
Can't you just call her anabcidiot and leave everyone alone?
嗨 看 孩子们 治疗猫
Hey,look,kids,therapy cat.
你撒谎 治疗动物是狗 不是猫
You're a liar. Therapyabcanimals are dogs,not cats.
你很争强好胜吗? 这是特别的
Aren't you feisty? This one's special.
如果她喜欢你 会有好事发生
If she likes you,interestingabcstuff happens.
孩子们 游戏时间结束
Uh,kids,playtime's over.
你知道吗 这是好事
You know what,this is a good thing.
你要么是在自我验证 这是健康的态度abc要么--
Because eitherabcyou're starti which is healthy,or--
我可不相信死神猫咪的传奇
I don't believe in theabclegend of good-bye kitty.
要么是你开始在乎别人的想法
Or you're starting to give aabccrap what other people think,
换个说法 你开始在乎其他人
which is just another way of sayingabcyou give a crap about other people.
我很想再多听点 但我不在乎abc还有 胶囊摄像机的结果出来了
I'd love to hear more of your theory,but Iabcdon't give a cra also the pillcam's back.
水蛭样 嵴状凸起
Polypoid. Raised edges.
考虑到这是通向阑尾的部分abc嵴状凸起是正常的
Raised edges are actually necessary,sinceabcthat's the opening to the appendix.
我们到底要看多少遍? 这儿没肿瘤
How many times are we gonnaabcwatch this? There's no tumor.
噢我的天 死神猫正在抓你的腿abc你就要死了
Oh,my god. The death cat is attackingabcyour legs. You're gonna die.
或许是那个跳跃的小红点吸引她了
Maybe it has something to do with thatabclittle red dot dancing around down there.
噢我的天 死之激光正在照射你的腿abc你就要死了
Oh,my god,the death laser isabcattacking your legs. You're gonna die.
我们在浪费时间
We're wasting time looking for cancer.
她还能走 算是很健康
She's still walking around.abcShe's still pretty healthy.
或许她得的不是什么大病
Maybe it's something minor.
或许不是在浪费时间
Maybe we're not wasting time.
我们不该发现平坦性病变
We wouldn't have seen a flat lesion.
皮肤癌能转移到肠 酷
Skin cancer could have metastasizedabcto the intestines. Cool.
查黑素瘤
Check for melanomas.
这儿 小猫 小猫来 这边
Here,kitty,kitty,kitty.abcCome here. Here,kitty.
什么事?
What?
不是癌症 我们在她背上发现了蜘蛛脉
It's not cancer. We foundabcspider veins on her back.
她刚来的时候没有
They weren't there when she came in.
蜘蛛脉意味着库欣氏症(皮质醇增多)abc可导致胃肠紊乱 褐色尿--
Spider veins means cushing's.Could cause anabcabdominal disturbance,brown urine--
支气管痉挛呢?
But the bronchospasm?
库欣氏肌病 不常见 但--
Cushing's myopathy.It'sabcuncommon but--
等等
wait a second.
你不会因为个非致死症状而吵醒我
You didn't wake me up to tell meabca symptom that's not killing her.
还有什么?
What else is going on?
我想她要死了
I think she's dying.
我说了是库欣氏
I just told you it's cushing'S.
我不是说由于蜘蛛脉abcLimpert先生死了
I don't mean because of theabcspider veins. Mr. Limpert died.
- 如果他是我高中健身教练--abc- 是那个昏迷的病人
- If that's my high school gymabcteacher-- - It's your coma patient.
他这一年半来都很稳定 突然就死了
He was stable for a yearabcand a half,and he just died.
猫是对的 House
The cat was right,house.
出来啊 小猫猫猫猫猫
Here,puss,puss,puss,pusspuss.
再说一声"猫"  连说6声 她就会现身
Say "puss" one more time. It's theabcsixth "puss" that really does it.
说得好 生闷气就能解决问题
You're right. Sulkingabcwill solve everything.
那猫蜷在我腿上 它肯定知道什么
That cat sat on my lap,andabcthat cat knows something.
你现在信了?
You believe it now?
昨天那是巧合
Yesterday it was all a coincidence.
我想无意中证明它不是
Yesterday it was until Iabcunintentionally proved it wasn'T.
她患的库欣氏综合症
Patient must have cushing'S.
我们要找到--
We have to figureabcout whether it's--
猫的嗅觉很灵 能闻出肝或肾衰竭
Cat's nose is powerful. It couldabcsmell liver or kidney failure.
正确 可要是你上午稍加留意abc传真过来的老人院档案文件
Exactly,except if you'd glanced at the nursingabchome files I had faxed over this morning,
你就知道大部分病人的肝和肾都没问题abc接着?
you'd know that most of the patients'abclivers and kidneys were fine;what else?
磁共振没显示库欣氏abc是在肾上腺还是在大脑发病
Mris aren't telling us if theabccushing's in her adrenals or her brain.
那就去查促肾上腺皮质激素
So check her A.C.T.H.
- 猫的视觉在光谱的蓝色端abc- 激素水平11.7
- A cat's vision is at the blue end of the spectrum.abc- A.C.T. H.Is 11.7.
无法分辨
It's too close to tell.
治疗错器官也无济于事
We can't treat the wrong organabc'cause that won't solveanything.
皮质醇剧烈增加 她会死的
She could have a cortisolabcstorm,could kill her.
又或许 你作为资深员工abc应该确保我的门关紧了
Well,maybe as the senior fellow you couldabchave made sure that my doors were closed,
这样我就能集中精力思考abc而不是一直寻找她
so that I could be concentrating onabcthe cat instead of looking for the cat.
你还好吧?
You all right?
你的鼻子
Your nose.
他说什么?
What'd he say?
好像是"喜欢酸梅汁吗?"
Sounds like he said,"doabcyou like cranberry juice?"
- 去死abc- 比假血便宜
- Crap.abc- Cheaper than fake blood.
而且酸酸甜甜
And more cran-tastic.
别让门再那样敞开
Don't ever leave myabcdoor open like that again.
你还有心情开玩笑 那女的快死了
You're playing pranks,andabcthis woman could be dying.
让Chase做个大脑静脉取样
So have chase do a venousabcsampling in her brain.
找到了 就在大脑
If he finds something,it's there.
没找到 就在肾上腺
If he finds nothing,it's the adrenals.
我不是以前的我了 我害怕
I'm not who I used to be. I'm scared.
这不是生活
That's not a way to live.
我想在你那儿工作
I want to come work for you.
天啊 你不会以为--abc我没有暗示现在就能雇你
Jeez,chris,you didn't think-- I didn't meanabcto imply that I could hire you right now.
你说你需要我这样的人
You said you needed guys like me.
我知道 但你没有工商管理硕士学位
I know,but you don't have an mba.
而且我刚雇了个首席医疗官
And I just hired a chief medical officer.
让我去搞那个激光刀手术abc我有点存款 虽然不是很多--
Let me invest in that laser scalpelabcstart-up. I got money saved.Not a ton but--
首轮融资最少需要两百万
We put ina $2 million minimumabcfor the first round financing.
我也许可以为你放宽条件
Look,I guess I could take youabcon at a smaller number.
但你要明白 不会很快就看到收益
But you have to understand,itabcwouldn't be some quick payoff.
我明白 这不会让我一夜暴富
I know,I know it's not gonnaabcchange my life overnight.
我只想改变
I just need to start changing it.
好 那就开始
Okay,then let's start.
你到底想在这个昏迷男体内找到什么?
What exactly are you hoping toabcfind inside your dead coma guy?
猫薄荷 狗骨头 不知道才找
Catnip. Chew toy. I don'tabcow. Th's why I'm looking.
病人在静脉取样时心脏停博
Your patient had cardiac arrestabcduring the venous sampling.
抢救了回来 但心脏依然很弱
We got her back,but herabcheart's still tenuous.
- 这说明?abc- 她很虚弱 快死了
- That tell us anything?abc- She's weak,possibly dying.
那就是没事
So nothing.
促肾上腺皮质激素呢?
What about the A.C.T.H.?
明显升高
Slighy elevated.
这说明库欣氏原发于脑--去吧
That confirms theabccushing's is in the brain--go.
你确定这是库欣氏?
Are you surethat it's cushing's?
通常会使人肥胖 她身材很好
You'd expect central bodyabcobesity. She's in good shape.
如果是通常情况abc也不会有猫咪牵扯其中了
If it had a normal presentation,thereabcwouldn't be a cat involved.
那就是脑
So it's the brain.
意味着下一步问题是移除脑垂体--
That means the next question is whetherabcto remove the pituitary right now--
这不是我的问题
That's not a question for me.
是病人的问题
That's a question for the patient.
两方面都告诉她 让她选
You'll present bothabcsides and let her decide.
好吧
All right.
我决定不告诉你我的理论了
I've gotta stop telling you my theories.
你总是想证明我错了
You always just try to prove me wrong.
就是那个Cuddy的屁股abc会在满月时变大的理论?
You mean the theory about cuddy'sabcass getting bigger at the full moon?
我确定了 照片还在博客里
I confirmed that one.abcPhoto's on my blog.
通常你会在病房恐吓病人听从你的指挥
Normally,you'd be up in the patientabcroom hectoring her on what to do.
而现在却在解剖不相干的
Instead you're up to your elbowsabcin some irrelevant dead guy
还不知道和魔法猫有没有关系的死尸
who may or may not beabcconnected to a magic cat
因为你想向我证明你不在乎
because you want to prove toabcme that you don't care.
案子了结 我在探求科学的奥秘
Case is over. I'm exploring aabcscientific mystery.
我能容忍你的探索精神
I put up with your obsessions.
甚至鼓励 只因为--它们能救命
I even encourage them,forabcone reason-- they save lives.
我不明白你现在在干什么
I don't know what you're doing now.
库欣氏综合症是指abc身体产生了过多的叫皮质醇的激素
Cushing's means your body'sabcoverproducing a hormone called cortisol.
推荐疗法是药物抑制
The recommended course of actionabcis to suppress it with drugs.
能治好吗?
And that will cure ?
只是抑制 停药便反弹
Just treat it. It could come back.
要根治只能开颅移除脑垂体
The only permanent solution is to cut intoabcyour brain and remove your pituitary gland,
但很危险
but the surgery's dangerous.
你的心脏已经停搏过一次
Your heart stopped onabcthe table once already.
我想做手术
I want the surgery.
如果我不先解决它 它就会结果我
This thing is gonna killabcme if I don't kill it first.
因为猫吗?
Because of the cat?
你是想说我有多傻吗?
Do you want to tellabcme what an idiot I'm being?
不
No.
我坚信有科学不能解释的事
I really believe that there areabcthings that science can't understand,
才有了信仰和祈祷
that there is a role forabcfaith and prayer,
在候诊室里可以这么想abc在手术室里可不行
but it's in the waitingabcroom,not the O.R.
我生病是有原因的
There's a reason I got sick.
坏事发生在我身上也是有原因的
There's a reason for all the badabcthings that have happened to me.
我不知道是什么原因 但我知道abc如果没有原因
I don't knowwhat that reason is,butabcI know thatif there isn't one,
如果世人都没有目标
if there's noabcgreater purpose in the world,
那将不是我想存在的世界
then it's not a world I want to live in.
我会安排手术的
I'll schedule an operating room.
早啊
Early.
我只待一会儿 我不干了
I'm not staying long. I'm quitting.
- 找到新工作?abc- 不是
- You got a new job?abc- No.
那你才不会辞职呢 明天见
Well,then you're not quitting.abcSee you back here tomorrow.
你不接受我辞职么?
You're not accepting my resignation?
这样省事点
Easier this way.
略过了你慌慌张张地跑回来求我abc我教训你一顿再给你复职的过程
It voids the whole thing where you panic,run backabcand grovel,and I punish you and then te you back.
再见了
Bye.
带点甜甜圈啊 人人都爱熊爪糕
Bring donuts. Everyoneabcloves those bear claws.
嘿 喵咪咪喵咪咪 喵喵咪?
Here,puss,puss,puss,puss,puss. Puss?
Taub先生
Mr. Taub.
我都等了一刻钟了 Neil在哪?
I've been waiting 15abcminutes. Where's neil?
Neil已经不在这工作了
Neil doesn't work here anymore.
他是执行总裁啊
He's the ceo.
很抱歉 我也很想帮您 抱歉
I'm sorry. I wish Iabccould help you. Sorry.
这太离谱了 我要和他的公司联合投资呢
This is crazy. I'mabcinvesting with his company.
他压根没有公司
He doesn't have a company.
他在这工作的时候 是个接待员 做临时工
He worked here,but heabcwas a receptionist,a temp.
- 他现在在哪?abc- 被拘留了
- Where is he?abc- He's in custody.
我真的不能再多说了
I really am not supposed toabcsay anything else.
我跟他是高中校友啊
I went to high school with him.
被他骗过的人都这么以为
That's what everyone else thought too.
我猜你也帮他治好了耳病吧?
I'm guessing youabcalso cured his ear problem.
- 你给他钱了么?abc- 还没有
- Did you give him the money yet?abc- No.
我是对的
I was right.
更让人快活的是 你错啦
And more satisfyingly,you were wrong.
这的确是个巧合
It was a coincidence.
那猫不是预知死亡
The cat was not predicting deaths.
它只是想找块暖和的地儿窝着
It was just trying to keep warm.
是啊 再没有比死人的身体abc更能发光发热的东西了
Yes,dead people areabcrenowned for their warm glow.
确实 其中有三个病人发烧了
They are if they're feverish,likeabcthree of the patients were.
不然就像另八个那样 日渐衰弱
Or if they're wastingabcaway,like the other eight.
- 消瘦并不能...abc- 绝对能
- Wasting doesn't--abc- Yeah,it does.
因为有人会为你盖电热毯
If it means someone sticks aabcheating blanket on you.
恭喜 多亏你没完没了纠缠这只猫abc才解开了这毫无意义的谜团
Congrats. Because of your crazy obsession withabcthis cat,you've solved a completely trivial mystery.
毫无意义 上帝啊
*****My god.
这明显只是较无意义
It's clearly only partially trivial.
Debbie也爬到Morgan身上了abc说明她也发烧了
Debbie climbed on morganabctoo,which means she was overheated.
究竟什么会导致面红 以及abc除中心体肥大之外的类库欣氏症候群呢?
So what causes flushing and mimics everyabccushing's symptom except central body obesity?
癌症
Cancer.
肠道类癌瘤会刺激促肾上腺皮质激素分泌
A corticotropin-producing carcinoidabctumor of the intestine.
但用胶囊摄像机什么都没看见啊
But your pillcam didn't find anything.
说明肿瘤肯定在abc胶囊摄像机到不了的地方
Means it must be somewhere theabcpillm couldn't go.
阑尾
The appendix.
恭喜 你恐怕救了她的命呢
Congratulations,youabcprobably saved her life.
至少肯定是把她abc从那没用的手术中救出来了
You definitely saved herabcneedless surgery.
是哦
Yes,I did.
手术室分机号是多少? 好奇问问
What's the O.R.Extensionabcnumber? Just curious.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我可不是来讨你一声谢的abc那多没风度
I wouldn't come here for thanks.abcThat would be ungracious.
我是来幸灾乐祸的
It's more about gloating.
就因为迷信 你就差点丢了块脑子
You were about to cut out a piece of yourabcbrain just to chase some crazy superstition.
但我没丢啊
But I didn't.
你啥忙都"没"帮上abc是我阻止这一切的
You "didn't" didn't doabcanything. I stopped it.
那你是怎么做到的?
And what made you do that?
科学 逻辑 推理 任选其三
Science,logic,reason. Pick any three.
那只猫偏偏选中那一刻abc跳到你电脑上
A cat chooses that exactabcmoment to sit on your computer.
也许是科学 逻辑和推理的功劳abc也许是别的呢
Maybe that's science and logic andabcreason or maybe it's something else.
你真是个白痴
You're an idiot.
我查过了纽约的那位传教士
I looked up theabcpreacher from new york state.
他的跟随者从未断绝过
His followers never faded out.
这些人成立了后来的abc基督复临安息日会 一个重要的教派
They became the seventh-dayabcadventists,a major religion.
那传教士改写了历史的进程啊
That man changed the course of history.
因为他的跟随者abc都跟他一样执迷不悟
Because his followers wereabcas deluded as he was.
也许他确实让他们找到了生活的意义
Maybe he just gaveabcthem something to live for.
感觉好些了
Feel better.
Kutner!
猫尿到我椅子上了?
Cat pee on my chair?
- 你还吐了我一脸血呢?abc- 那是假血好吧!
- Blood on my face?abc- Fake blood.
干洗费你来付
You pay for the dry cleaning.
你咋还能活着?
Why are you still alive?
我也不确定
I'm not sure.
我敢说他被你的坚决反抗雷到了
I guess he was impressed youabcstood up to him.
- 还让只猫尿在他椅子上abc- 是啊
- And got a cat to pee on his chair.abc- Yeah.
是只"猫"
A cat.
- 明天见abc- 行
- See you tomorrow.abc- Yeah.